<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>skemman.is</title>
    <link>http://skemman.is</link>
    <description>Ritgerðir birtar á skemman.is</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>is</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:12:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Warming Climate and Land Use Change on Ecosystem Processes in Icelandic Rangelands as Mediated by Plants</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52065</link>
      <description>Effects of Warming Climate and Land Use Change on Ecosystem Processes in Icelandic Rangelands as Mediated by Plants - Axel Ingi Einarsson 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52065</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Historical Sea Ice Dynamics in Baffin Bay and the Davis Strait: 1820-1889: A Spatio-Temporal Analysis</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52064</link>
      <description>Historical Sea Ice Dynamics in Baffin Bay and the Davis Strait: 1820-1889: A Spatio-Temporal Analysis - Jonah Alexander Smith 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52064</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concurrent Monads in 2-Categories</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52063</link>
      <description>Concurrent Monads in 2-Categories - Bjarki Gunnarsson 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52063</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vistfræði Hypoponera spp. (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) á íslenskum jarðhitasvæðum</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52066</link>
      <description>Vistfræði Hypoponera spp. (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) á íslenskum jarðhitasvæðum - Andreas Guðmundsson Gähwiller 2001-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52066</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ecological Footprint of Reykjavík: Downscaling National Accounts and Informing Municipal Policy</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52067</link>
      <description>Ecological Footprint of Reykjavík: Downscaling National Accounts and Informing Municipal Policy - Rakel Bærings Halldórsdóttir 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The impact of environmental volunteering on nature conservation: The case of Iceland Conservation Volunteers.</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52068</link>
      <description>The impact of environmental volunteering on nature conservation: The case of Iceland Conservation Volunteers. - Sebastian Diaz Duran 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of Norbornene-Functionalised Macromonomers for Bottlebrush Polymers via ROMP: Characterisation and ROMP behaviour of polystyrene- and methoxy poly(ethylene glycol)-based macromonomers</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52069</link>
      <description>Synthesis of Norbornene-Functionalised Macromonomers for Bottlebrush Polymers via ROMP: Characterisation and ROMP behaviour of polystyrene- and methoxy poly(ethylene glycol)-based macromonomers - Katrín Marey Magnúsdóttir 2002-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gul stéttarfélög eru jafnan talin andstæð grundvallarhugmyndum félagafrelsis. Að hvaða marki endurspegla þau, ásamt öðrum atriðum á borð við forgangsréttarákvæði og íhlutun atvinnurekenda, kerfislægar áskoranir við að tryggja sjálfstæði stéttarfélaga samkvæmt alþjóðlegum vinnuréttarviðmiðum?</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52059</link>
      <description>Gul stéttarfélög eru jafnan talin andstæð grundvallarhugmyndum félagafrelsis. Að hvaða marki endurspegla þau, ásamt öðrum atriðum á borð við forgangsréttarákvæði og íhlutun atvinnurekenda, kerfislægar áskoranir við að tryggja sjálfstæði stéttarfélaga samkvæmt alþjóðlegum vinnuréttarviðmiðum? - Sara Gunnarsdóttir 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development and testing of an innovative system for measurement of ultrasound modulation of electrical current in volume conductor</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52062</link>
      <description>Development and testing of an innovative system for measurement of ultrasound modulation of electrical current in volume conductor - Davíð Arnljótur Karlsson 1992-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reliability of smartwatches in the management and follow-up of patients with Atrial fibrillation on the waiting list for ablation</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52060</link>
      <description>Reliability of smartwatches in the management and follow-up of patients with Atrial fibrillation on the waiting list for ablation - Herdís Kristjánsdóttir 1992-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52060</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ferlagreining á AutoStore kerfi: Rannsókn á vöruhúsi Parlogis ehf. á Hólmsheiði í þróunarstigi</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52058</link>
      <description>Ferlagreining á AutoStore kerfi: Rannsókn á vöruhúsi Parlogis ehf. á Hólmsheiði í þróunarstigi - Hilmir Jónsson 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ástandsgreining spenna</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52057</link>
      <description>Ástandsgreining spenna - Hilmir Dan Gíslason 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of a 3D bioprinted hydrogel model to study Hedgehog signalling in Chondrocytes</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52049</link>
      <description>Development of a 3D bioprinted hydrogel model to study Hedgehog signalling in Chondrocytes - Sindri Snær Jónsson 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Users’ Understanding of Formulas, Static and Dynamic Sketches as Representations of Spreadsheet Operations</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52048</link>
      <description>Comparing Users’ Understanding of Formulas, Static and Dynamic Sketches as Representations of Spreadsheet Operations - Kristín Eva Ólafsdóttir 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>„Mér finnst þau bara svo til í hlutina“ Reynsla og viðhorf hönnunar- og smíðakennara til áhugahvatar grunnskólanemenda</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52056</link>
      <description>„Mér finnst þau bara svo til í hlutina“ Reynsla og viðhorf hönnunar- og smíðakennara til áhugahvatar grunnskólanemenda - Signý Traustadóttir 1974-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52056</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extreme Rare-Event Modelling of Verification Errors in Automated Pill Scanners</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52051</link>
      <description>Extreme Rare-Event Modelling of Verification Errors in Automated Pill Scanners - Karl Leó Sigurþórsson 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-resolution spatio-temporal analysis reveals the dynamic evolution of earthquake swarms around Askja–Herðubreið, Northern Volcanic Zone Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52054</link>
      <description>High-resolution spatio-temporal analysis reveals the dynamic evolution of earthquake swarms around Askja–Herðubreið, Northern Volcanic Zone Iceland - Hugo Alejandro Arteaga Vivas 1989-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating reliable people data : advancing HR through structured quality-management practices</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52052</link>
      <description>Creating reliable people data : advancing HR through structured quality-management practices - Anna Lotta Michaelsdóttir 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52052</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-agent reinforcement learning for order dispatching and sequencing in on-demand food delivery platforms</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52053</link>
      <description>Multi-agent reinforcement learning for order dispatching and sequencing in on-demand food delivery platforms - Yuang Yang 2001-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foreign residents’ awareness and response to volcanic risks from Katla volcano: Insights from Vík in Mýrdal, South Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52050</link>
      <description>Foreign residents’ awareness and response to volcanic risks from Katla volcano: Insights from Vík in Mýrdal, South Iceland - Diana Sól Editudóttir 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52050</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Afgösun hitaveituvatns í gasskiljum : helstu hönnunarforsendur</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52055</link>
      <description>Afgösun hitaveituvatns í gasskiljum : helstu hönnunarforsendur - Pétur Freyr Sigurjónsson 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of a low-overhead NFC-based mobile receipt system</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52061</link>
      <description>Design of a low-overhead NFC-based mobile receipt system - Eyþór Mikael Eyþórsson 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>V–laga, kambrað, ósamhverft, framdrifið vængsegl : loftaflfræðileg greining og stýring á ómönnuðu yfirborðsfari</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52033</link>
      <description>V–laga, kambrað, ósamhverft, framdrifið vængsegl : loftaflfræðileg greining og stýring á ómönnuðu yfirborðsfari - Lukasz Serwatko 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52033</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decomposing and Analysing Hot Water Usage in an Icelandic District Heating System Using Hourly Smart Meter Data</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52035</link>
      <description>Decomposing and Analysing Hot Water Usage in an Icelandic District Heating System Using Hourly Smart Meter Data - Adam John Gerald Ursell 2001-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leiðin að jákvæðri vinnustaðamenningu „Að finna jákvæðni og bjartsýni daglega getur ekki annað en verið til góðs“</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52032</link>
      <description>Leiðin að jákvæðri vinnustaðamenningu „Að finna jákvæðni og bjartsýni daglega getur ekki annað en verið til góðs“ - Inga Birna Sigurðardóttir 1974-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/52032</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
