<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>skemman.is</title>
    <link>http://skemman.is</link>
    <description>Ritgerðir birtar á skemman.is</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>is</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 08:00:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Tuberculosis vaccination coverage and risk factors for incomplete vaccination among children five years and younger in the Manica and Sofala provinces of Mozambique</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44741</link>
      <description>Tuberculosis vaccination coverage and risk factors for incomplete vaccination among children five years and younger in the Manica and Sofala provinces of Mozambique - Marissa Wan Lynn Tousey-Pfarrer 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44741</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tengsl útundanótta við sálfélagslegar breytur: Hlutverk félagslegs samanburðar og þarfarinnar fyrir að tilheyra</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44743</link>
      <description>Tengsl útundanótta við sálfélagslegar breytur: Hlutverk félagslegs samanburðar og þarfarinnar fyrir að tilheyra - Kolbrún Jónsdóttir 1986-; Agnes Hekla Árnadóttir 1992-; Agnes Sigurðardóttir 1978-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44743</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative life cycle assessment of hydrogen production in Iceland and the EU-27</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44747</link>
      <description>Comparative life cycle assessment of hydrogen production in Iceland and the EU-27 - Drew Jacob Barron 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adolescents who struggle with substance use following domestic violence in their childhood</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44744</link>
      <description>Adolescents who struggle with substance use following domestic violence in their childhood - Birna Lind Pálmadóttir 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44744</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Examining gratitude in children and youth with disabilities : is there a difference between children and youth with motor disabilities and intellectual disabilities?</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44746</link>
      <description>Examining gratitude in children and youth with disabilities : is there a difference between children and youth with motor disabilities and intellectual disabilities? - Kara Björk Sævarsdóttir 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44746</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Viðhorf nýlegra útskrifaðra ljósmæðra til eðlilegra fæðinga og verndun þeirra á Fæðingarvakt Landspítala: Eigindlega viðtalsrannsókn</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44758</link>
      <description>Viðhorf nýlegra útskrifaðra ljósmæðra til eðlilegra fæðinga og verndun þeirra á Fæðingarvakt Landspítala: Eigindlega viðtalsrannsókn - Sunna Líf Guðmundsdóttir 1989-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hverjar eru ástæður þess að hraustum nýburum er gefin ábót á fyrstu viku eftir fæðingu á sjúkrahúsi og hvaða leiðir eru til úrbóta? Kerfisbundin fræðileg samantekt</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44759</link>
      <description>Hverjar eru ástæður þess að hraustum nýburum er gefin ábót á fyrstu viku eftir fæðingu á sjúkrahúsi og hvaða leiðir eru til úrbóta? Kerfisbundin fræðileg samantekt - Tinna Halldórsdóttir 1982-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44759</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mental toughness in Icelandic female football players : comparisons of the national team, top and second top women's divisions</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44761</link>
      <description>Mental toughness in Icelandic female football players : comparisons of the national team, top and second top women's divisions - Dagrún Birta Karlsdóttir 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of school-based light intervention on daytime napping and daytime sleepiness among adolescents in Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44762</link>
      <description>Effects of school-based light intervention on daytime napping and daytime sleepiness among adolescents in Iceland - Ingibjörg Patricia Magnúsdóttir 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44762</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tilgangur : rekstrarafleiðingar í hluta- og einkahlutafélögum þegar teknar eru ákvarðanir andstætt skráðum tilgangi</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44763</link>
      <description>Tilgangur : rekstrarafleiðingar í hluta- og einkahlutafélögum þegar teknar eru ákvarðanir andstætt skráðum tilgangi - Vilhelmína Ómarsdóttir 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44763</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The importance of social support in times of COVID-19 and its protective factor for adolescents’ anxiety</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44760</link>
      <description>The importance of social support in times of COVID-19 and its protective factor for adolescents’ anxiety - Sæunn Ýr Óskarsdóttir 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44760</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge and attitudes toward electroconvulsive therapy (ECT) among mental health workers and the public in Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44766</link>
      <description>Knowledge and attitudes toward electroconvulsive therapy (ECT) among mental health workers and the public in Iceland - Díana Sif Ingadóttir 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44766</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-esteem as a mediator of the effects of parental involvement on anxiety and depression</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44765</link>
      <description>Self-esteem as a mediator of the effects of parental involvement on anxiety and depression - Kolfinna Pétursdóttir 2001-; Steinþór Örn Helgason 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44765</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risk management and value creation : an international high-tech manufacturing company´s approach to risk management and value creation in new product development projects</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44764</link>
      <description>Risk management and value creation : an international high-tech manufacturing company´s approach to risk management and value creation in new product development projects - Eyjólfur Alexandersson 1981-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44764</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Þau eru bara eins og aðrir"  Starfsnám og þróun starfsferils nemenda með fötlun á starfsbraut í framhaldsskóla</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44801</link>
      <description>"Þau eru bara eins og aðrir"  Starfsnám og þróun starfsferils nemenda með fötlun á starfsbraut í framhaldsskóla - Aðalheiður Reynisdóttir 1964-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stillbirth and trauma associated sleep disturbances: A population-based study of 27,605 women</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44749</link>
      <description>Stillbirth and trauma associated sleep disturbances: A population-based study of 27,605 women - Marsibil Ósk Helgadóttir 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44749</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eldri mæður og útkomur nýbura á Íslandi á 10 ára  tímabili. Lýðgrunduð gagnagrunnsrannsókn á gögnum úr fæðingaskrá</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44802</link>
      <description>Eldri mæður og útkomur nýbura á Íslandi á 10 ára  tímabili. Lýðgrunduð gagnagrunnsrannsókn á gögnum úr fæðingaskrá - Hugrún Jóna Hilmarsdóttir 1988-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44802</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Almenningsrými í úthverfi Reykjavíkur. Forsendur og hönnunartillögur fyrir Selás</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44805</link>
      <description>Almenningsrými í úthverfi Reykjavíkur. Forsendur og hönnunartillögur fyrir Selás - Helga Guðný Þorgrímsdóttir 1988-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44805</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Landslag innan arkitektúrs</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44804</link>
      <description>Landslag innan arkitektúrs - Birgitta Ösp Atladóttir 1982-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44804</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hönnunartillaga að útivistarsvæði við Litludalsá á Patreksfirði</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44803</link>
      <description>Hönnunartillaga að útivistarsvæði við Litludalsá á Patreksfirði - Tinna Holt Victorsdóttir 1988-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44803</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heilsueflandi útkomur í ljósmæðraþjónustu á Íslandi. Þróun og forprófun á útkomubreytum í fæðingu</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44754</link>
      <description>Heilsueflandi útkomur í ljósmæðraþjónustu á Íslandi. Þróun og forprófun á útkomubreytum í fæðingu - Ilmur Sól Eiríksdóttir 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44754</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of a dynamic software guide for the usage of Kiso's surface electromyography sensors</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44775</link>
      <description>Development of a dynamic software guide for the usage of Kiso's surface electromyography sensors - Bjarki Laxdal Baldursson 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44775</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing commodity price volatility : an analysis of risk measurements and hedging strategies with derivatives</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44768</link>
      <description>Managing commodity price volatility : an analysis of risk measurements and hedging strategies with derivatives - Hrefna Þuríður Leifsdóttir 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44768</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-validation of new oral reading fluency criteria  based on empirical data from Icelandic elmentary  students</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44771</link>
      <description>Cross-validation of new oral reading fluency criteria  based on empirical data from Icelandic elmentary  students - Orri Gautur Finnbogason 1999-; Óliver Haraldsson 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44771</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sussex-Oxford Compassion Scales : psychometric properties of the Icelandic version and correlation with well-being</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44773</link>
      <description>The Sussex-Oxford Compassion Scales : psychometric properties of the Icelandic version and correlation with well-being - María Nína Gunnarsdóttir 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44773</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
