<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>skemman.is</title>
    <link>http://skemman.is</link>
    <description>Ritgerðir birtar á skemman.is</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>is</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 10:00:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Tuberculosis vaccination coverage and risk factors for incomplete vaccination among children five years and younger in the Manica and Sofala provinces of Mozambique</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44741</link>
      <description>Tuberculosis vaccination coverage and risk factors for incomplete vaccination among children five years and younger in the Manica and Sofala provinces of Mozambique - Marissa Wan Lynn Tousey-Pfarrer 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44741</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tengsl útundanótta við sálfélagslegar breytur: Hlutverk félagslegs samanburðar og þarfarinnar fyrir að tilheyra</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44743</link>
      <description>Tengsl útundanótta við sálfélagslegar breytur: Hlutverk félagslegs samanburðar og þarfarinnar fyrir að tilheyra - Kolbrún Jónsdóttir 1986-; Agnes Hekla Árnadóttir 1992-; Agnes Sigurðardóttir 1978-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44743</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative life cycle assessment of hydrogen production in Iceland and the EU-27</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44747</link>
      <description>Comparative life cycle assessment of hydrogen production in Iceland and the EU-27 - Drew Jacob Barron 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adolescents who struggle with substance use following domestic violence in their childhood</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44744</link>
      <description>Adolescents who struggle with substance use following domestic violence in their childhood - Birna Lind Pálmadóttir 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44744</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Examining gratitude in children and youth with disabilities : is there a difference between children and youth with motor disabilities and intellectual disabilities?</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44746</link>
      <description>Examining gratitude in children and youth with disabilities : is there a difference between children and youth with motor disabilities and intellectual disabilities? - Kara Björk Sævarsdóttir 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44746</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Örmögnun og vinnutengt þunglyndi: Aðgreining á grundvelli ólíkra áhrifaþátta</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44742</link>
      <description>Örmögnun og vinnutengt þunglyndi: Aðgreining á grundvelli ólíkra áhrifaþátta - Melkorka Arnarsdóttir 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44742</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The association of ADHD and self-esteem among university students</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44745</link>
      <description>The association of ADHD and self-esteem among university students - Guðrún Ýr Bjarnadóttir 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44745</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating venture capital : an examination of strategies, decisions, and models</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44748</link>
      <description>Navigating venture capital : an examination of strategies, decisions, and models - Stefán Jónsson 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44748</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stillbirth and trauma associated sleep disturbances: A population-based study of 27,605 women</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44749</link>
      <description>Stillbirth and trauma associated sleep disturbances: A population-based study of 27,605 women - Marsibil Ósk Helgadóttir 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44749</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Usage and attitudes toward pornography among young adults in Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44751</link>
      <description>Usage and attitudes toward pornography among young adults in Iceland - Ingunn Eva Reynisdóttir 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44751</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Icelandic startups dream of project management? : exploring the experience of participants in Icelandic business accelerators</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44752</link>
      <description>Do Icelandic startups dream of project management? : exploring the experience of participants in Icelandic business accelerators - Jóhannes Ingi Árnason 1982-; Sigrún Inga Kristinsdóttir 1971-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44752</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sjálfbær stjórnun : mat á upplýsingagjöf og stjórnarháttum fyrirtækja​</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44750</link>
      <description>Sjálfbær stjórnun : mat á upplýsingagjöf og stjórnarháttum fyrirtækja​ - Kristín Ösp Þorleifsdóttir 1979-; Rósa Guðrún Erlingsdóttir 1970-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44750</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effects of different parenting styles on self-esteem</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44753</link>
      <description>The effects of different parenting styles on self-esteem - Rakel Guðjónsdóttir 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44753</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heilsueflandi útkomur í ljósmæðraþjónustu á Íslandi. Þróun og forprófun á útkomubreytum í fæðingu</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44754</link>
      <description>Heilsueflandi útkomur í ljósmæðraþjónustu á Íslandi. Þróun og forprófun á útkomubreytum í fæðingu - Ilmur Sól Eiríksdóttir 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44754</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tengsl mótþróaþrjóskuröskunar og félagsfærni barna: Slembuð klínísk samanburðarrannsókn á áhrifum tveggja ólíkra meðferða</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44715</link>
      <description>Tengsl mótþróaþrjóskuröskunar og félagsfærni barna: Slembuð klínísk samanburðarrannsókn á áhrifum tveggja ólíkra meðferða - Karen Embla Guðmundsdóttir 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44715</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of regularity in redundancy masking</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44717</link>
      <description>The role of regularity in redundancy masking - Arnleif Margrét Friðriksdóttir 1989-; Ari Kárason 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44717</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prevalence and Trajectory of Depressive Symptoms Among COVID-19 Infected Individuals:  An Icelandic Cohort Study</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44738</link>
      <description>Prevalence and Trajectory of Depressive Symptoms Among COVID-19 Infected Individuals:  An Icelandic Cohort Study - Íris Ósk Bjarnadóttir 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44738</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Media recycling in commercial scale : Spirulina platensis cultivation</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44739</link>
      <description>Media recycling in commercial scale : Spirulina platensis cultivation - Alexandria Rae Massey 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44739</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lower Extremity Functional Scale; Psychometric properties of the Icelandic version</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44736</link>
      <description>The Lower Extremity Functional Scale; Psychometric properties of the Icelandic version - Sara Benediktsdóttir 1987-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44736</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Er kynbundin skekkja í mati á leiklýsendum?</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44737</link>
      <description>Er kynbundin skekkja í mati á leiklýsendum? - Guðjóna Björk Þorbjarnardóttir 1987-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44737</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getur opinberi geirinn lært af einkageiranum? : samanburður á Fjarðabyggð og Norðuráli</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44740</link>
      <description>Getur opinberi geirinn lært af einkageiranum? : samanburður á Fjarðabyggð og Norðuráli - Jón Steinar Guðlaugsson 1986-; Magnús Árni Gunnarsson 1981-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44740</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contextual role of azithromycin as a potential inhibitor of epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition in lung epithelium</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44735</link>
      <description>Contextual role of azithromycin as a potential inhibitor of epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition in lung epithelium - Svandís Davíðsdóttir 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44735</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tengsl Milou miðlægs fósturhjartsláttarkerfis við útkomu fæðinga á Landspítala: Afturvirk ferilrannsókn</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44731</link>
      <description>Tengsl Milou miðlægs fósturhjartsláttarkerfis við útkomu fæðinga á Landspítala: Afturvirk ferilrannsókn - Birta Hildardóttir 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44731</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tíðni eðlilegra fæðinga eftir sameiningu fæðingardeilda á Landspítala Afturvirk ferilrannsókn á langtímaáhrifum fyrirbyggjandi aðgerða</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44716</link>
      <description>Tíðni eðlilegra fæðinga eftir sameiningu fæðingardeilda á Landspítala Afturvirk ferilrannsókn á langtímaáhrifum fyrirbyggjandi aðgerða - Ragnhildur Anna Ólafsdóttir 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44716</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing psychometric properties of the Acceptance and Action Questionnaire-II (AAQ-II), the Cognitive Fusion Questionnaire (CFQ), and the Valuing Questionnaire (VQ)</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44728</link>
      <description>Assessing psychometric properties of the Acceptance and Action Questionnaire-II (AAQ-II), the Cognitive Fusion Questionnaire (CFQ), and the Valuing Questionnaire (VQ) - Helga Margrét Rúnarsdóttir 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44728</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
