<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>skemman.is</title>
    <link>http://skemman.is</link>
    <description>Ritgerðir birtar á skemman.is</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>is</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 09:00:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Hálsæðaflysjun á Íslandi: faraldsfræði, meðferð og horfur</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47488</link>
      <description>Hálsæðaflysjun á Íslandi: faraldsfræði, meðferð og horfur - Iðunn Andradóttir 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47488</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hver á að sinna systkinum fatlaðra barna?  Þjónusta við systkini fatlaðra barna</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47489</link>
      <description>Hver á að sinna systkinum fatlaðra barna?  Þjónusta við systkini fatlaðra barna - Dagmar Ósk Guðmundsdóttir 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of FGD5-AS1 in Osteosarcoma</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47490</link>
      <description>The role of FGD5-AS1 in Osteosarcoma - Zara Ahmad 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47490</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>„Ég held að margir taki því sem rosalega sjálfsögðum hlut að eiga góða og heilbrigða fjölskyldu“ : Sýn fullorðinna einstaklinga á eigin reynslu af því að eiga foreldri sem glímir við geðrænan vanda</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47467</link>
      <description>„Ég held að margir taki því sem rosalega sjálfsögðum hlut að eiga góða og heilbrigða fjölskyldu“ : Sýn fullorðinna einstaklinga á eigin reynslu af því að eiga foreldri sem glímir við geðrænan vanda - Hulda Björg Guðmundsdóttir 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47467</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring stress levels and work-family conflict among parents of children with health issues : the moderating role of workplace social support and financial concerns</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47466</link>
      <description>Exploring stress levels and work-family conflict among parents of children with health issues : the moderating role of workplace social support and financial concerns - María Björg Fjölnisdóttir 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47466</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notkun almennings á heilbrigðiskerfinu: Mæling komutíðni á spítala og heilsugæslur á Íslandi</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47463</link>
      <description>Notkun almennings á heilbrigðiskerfinu: Mæling komutíðni á spítala og heilsugæslur á Íslandi - Jón Pétur Snæland 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47463</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The relationship between trauma or mental health challenges and the personal motivation to study psychology in an Icelandic sample</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47468</link>
      <description>The relationship between trauma or mental health challenges and the personal motivation to study psychology in an Icelandic sample - Guðný Ása Halldórsdóttir 2002-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47468</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The association between chronotype and sleep quality in adolescents : does screen time have a mediating role?</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47464</link>
      <description>The association between chronotype and sleep quality in adolescents : does screen time have a mediating role? - Rósa Kristín Björnsdóttir 2002-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47464</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do Icelanders evaluate others on dating apps that make them swipe right?</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47465</link>
      <description>How do Icelanders evaluate others on dating apps that make them swipe right? - Ingibjörg Sara Sævarsdóttir 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47465</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Umskipti frá flúrperum yfir í LED: Hvati til orkusparnaðar</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47462</link>
      <description>Umskipti frá flúrperum yfir í LED: Hvati til orkusparnaðar - Sigríður Erla Ólafsdóttir 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47462</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parental support and parental monitoring and relations to deviant behaviors among adolescent boys and girls in Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47486</link>
      <description>Parental support and parental monitoring and relations to deviant behaviors among adolescent boys and girls in Iceland - Alexandra Marín Sveinsdóttir 1999-; Sara Ösp Eðvarðsdóttir 1991-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47486</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reynsla kvenna af yfirsetu ljósmóður í fæðingu: Þýðing og staðfæring spurningalistans PPI</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47485</link>
      <description>Reynsla kvenna af yfirsetu ljósmóður í fæðingu: Þýðing og staðfæring spurningalistans PPI - Hulda Viktorsdóttir 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47485</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Incidence and impact of violence and availability of support among Icelandic inmates</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47483</link>
      <description>Incidence and impact of violence and availability of support among Icelandic inmates - Kristel Dögg Vilhjálmsdóttir 1986-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brjóstagjafaráðgjöf á Íslandi - Innsýn í helstu verkefni og áskoranir: Eigindleg rýnihóparannsókn</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47478</link>
      <description>Brjóstagjafaráðgjöf á Íslandi - Innsýn í helstu verkefni og áskoranir: Eigindleg rýnihóparannsókn - Stefanía Elsa Jónsdóttir 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47478</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women and pornography : do women watch pornography and what are their experiences in their sexual lives?</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47481</link>
      <description>Women and pornography : do women watch pornography and what are their experiences in their sexual lives? - Katrín Jónsdóttir 2001-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring text reading fluency across grades :  addressing potential test bias</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47482</link>
      <description>Measuring text reading fluency across grades :  addressing potential test bias - Davíð Örn Hugus 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47482</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changes in stress among Icelandic university students following a global pandemic.</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47480</link>
      <description>Changes in stress among Icelandic university students following a global pandemic. - Ásta Guðrún Ragnarsdóttir 2002-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47480</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The integration of intercultural competencies and intercultural skills into the English subject in the Greek, Icelandic, and Swedish lower secondary school curricula</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47484</link>
      <description>The integration of intercultural competencies and intercultural skills into the English subject in the Greek, Icelandic, and Swedish lower secondary school curricula - Christos Raptis 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47484</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The impact of social media on infidelity, insecurities, and intimacy in romantic relationships</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47479</link>
      <description>The impact of social media on infidelity, insecurities, and intimacy in romantic relationships - Erna Saga Sigfúsdóttir 2002-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47479</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>„Smá eins og mömmur manns í gegnum þetta“ Væntingar íslenskra kvenna til umönnunar ljósmóður í fæðingu</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47461</link>
      <description>„Smá eins og mömmur manns í gegnum þetta“ Væntingar íslenskra kvenna til umönnunar ljósmóður í fæðingu - Agla Bettý Andrésdóttir 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47461</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forvarnir og meðferð án lyfja við stálma, stíflum og brjóstabólgu. Kerfisbundin fræðileg samantekt</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47477</link>
      <description>Forvarnir og meðferð án lyfja við stálma, stíflum og brjóstabólgu. Kerfisbundin fræðileg samantekt - Oddný Silja Friðriksdóttir 1987-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>,,Mitt örugga rými" Reynsla kvenna af fæðingum án fagaðila á Íslandi. Fyrirbærifræðileg rannsókn</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47476</link>
      <description>,,Mitt örugga rými" Reynsla kvenna af fæðingum án fagaðila á Íslandi. Fyrirbærifræðileg rannsókn - Guðrún Magnúsdóttir 1989-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47476</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The impact of 2001 : A Space Odyssey on attitudes towards artificial intelligence and fear of the unknown</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47471</link>
      <description>The impact of 2001 : A Space Odyssey on attitudes towards artificial intelligence and fear of the unknown - Alexander Þór Gunnarsson 2001-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47471</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effects of toy accessibility and organisation on student’s Play and teachers’ play engagement in a special education school in Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47472</link>
      <description>The effects of toy accessibility and organisation on student’s Play and teachers’ play engagement in a special education school in Iceland - Hildur María Arnalds 2001-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47472</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The relationship between childhood traumatic experiences, mental health, and substance use, among youth in Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47469</link>
      <description>The relationship between childhood traumatic experiences, mental health, and substance use, among youth in Iceland - Eva Egilsdóttir 2002-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47469</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
