<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>skemman.is</title>
    <link>http://skemman.is</link>
    <description>Ritgerðir birtar á skemman.is</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>is</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 17:00:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Túlkun staðlaðra samningsskilmála með hliðsjón af andskýringarreglu samningaréttar</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45875</link>
      <description>Túlkun staðlaðra samningsskilmála með hliðsjón af andskýringarreglu samningaréttar - Árni Svavar Johnsen 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45875</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Association Analysis of Significant Life Stressors and BMI with Frequentist and Bayesian Methodology, Approaches for Interaction Analysis Evaluated with Simulations</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45874</link>
      <description>Association Analysis of Significant Life Stressors and BMI with Frequentist and Bayesian Methodology, Approaches for Interaction Analysis Evaluated with Simulations - Sigurbjörg Anna Guðnadóttir 1971-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45874</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of MITF in autophagy and oxidative stress in human retinal epithelial cells</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45873</link>
      <description>The role of MITF in autophagy and oxidative stress in human retinal epithelial cells - Kristján Hermannsson 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45873</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kornforði, fjársjóður Íslands? Rannsókn á hagkvæmni uppbyggingar neyðarkornbirgða fyrir kjarnfóðurframleiðslu</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45872</link>
      <description>Kornforði, fjársjóður Íslands? Rannsókn á hagkvæmni uppbyggingar neyðarkornbirgða fyrir kjarnfóðurframleiðslu - Karl Liljendal Hólmgeirsson 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45872</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>218. gr. b. almennra hegningarlaga nr. 19/1940</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45871</link>
      <description>218. gr. b. almennra hegningarlaga nr. 19/1940 - Þórunn Marinósdóttir 1972-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45871</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effect of previous preterm birth on the risk of recurrent preterm birth in Iceland 1997-2018</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45870</link>
      <description>The effect of previous preterm birth on the risk of recurrent preterm birth in Iceland 1997-2018 - Ása Dóra Gylfadóttir 1991-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45870</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prognosis of whiplash-associated disorders following a car collision - A systematic review of prognostic factors</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45869</link>
      <description>Prognosis of whiplash-associated disorders following a car collision - A systematic review of prognostic factors - Védís Gissurardóttir 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45869</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Variation in shoaling behavior in lake Mývatn threespine stickleback in relation to temperature and origin</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45851</link>
      <description>Variation in shoaling behavior in lake Mývatn threespine stickleback in relation to temperature and origin - Spencer William Edwards 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45851</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microplastic concentrations in sea surface waters of Skjálfandi Bay : Iceland and the potential impacts on baleen whales</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45860</link>
      <description>Microplastic concentrations in sea surface waters of Skjálfandi Bay : Iceland and the potential impacts on baleen whales - Eleanor Frances Young 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45860</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple stressor effects on morphology of Zostera marina, its erosion mitigation capacity and shoot dislodgement, in the Turku Archipelago, Finland.</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45854</link>
      <description>Multiple stressor effects on morphology of Zostera marina, its erosion mitigation capacity and shoot dislodgement, in the Turku Archipelago, Finland. - Riitta Maila Chorfi 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45854</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can sailing tourism and marine research benefit from each other? :  An arctic case study with particular focus on Iceland and Northern Norway</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45853</link>
      <description>Can sailing tourism and marine research benefit from each other? :  An arctic case study with particular focus on Iceland and Northern Norway - Hugo Vancraenenbroeck 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45853</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dutch shipping industry's perceptions on climate change mitigation regulations applied to the industry :  an overview of the challenges and opportunities the industry experiences with climate change mitigation efforts</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45859</link>
      <description>The Dutch shipping industry's perceptions on climate change mitigation regulations applied to the industry :  an overview of the challenges and opportunities the industry experiences with climate change mitigation efforts - Stephany van den Bosch 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45859</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Narratives of and perspectives on seaweed farming for a more sustainable future</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45858</link>
      <description>Narratives of and perspectives on seaweed farming for a more sustainable future - Celia Norman Garrity 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45858</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The non-silent world : acoustic responses of white-beaked dolphins (lagenorhynchus albirostris) to changes in maritime traffic : a case study during the covid-19 anthropause in Skjálfandi Bay, Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45856</link>
      <description>The non-silent world : acoustic responses of white-beaked dolphins (lagenorhynchus albirostris) to changes in maritime traffic : a case study during the covid-19 anthropause in Skjálfandi Bay, Iceland - Mathieu Reverberi 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45856</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting course for sustainability : evaluating resident‘s perspectives of cruise tourism in Ísafjörður, Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45855</link>
      <description>Setting course for sustainability : evaluating resident‘s perspectives of cruise tourism in Ísafjörður, Iceland - Elizabeth Riendeau 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45855</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benthic habitat mapping in offshore Qeqertarsuaq Tunua, West Greenland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45852</link>
      <description>Benthic habitat mapping in offshore Qeqertarsuaq Tunua, West Greenland - Joyce Mulder 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45852</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marine litter as a vector for fouling species in the southwest, northeast, and Westfjords of Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45857</link>
      <description>Marine litter as a vector for fouling species in the southwest, northeast, and Westfjords of Iceland - Holly Athalie Solloway 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45857</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ᓄᓇᕗᑦ - Our land : on policies and guidelines regarding sustainable community design and Inuit self-determination in Nunavut</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45866</link>
      <description>ᓄᓇᕗᑦ - Our land : on policies and guidelines regarding sustainable community design and Inuit self-determination in Nunavut - Arina Nikolaeva 1989-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45866</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fine-scale movement of humpback whales (Megaptera novaeangliae) in Icelandic coastal waters</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45865</link>
      <description>Fine-scale movement of humpback whales (Megaptera novaeangliae) in Icelandic coastal waters - Sydni Anne Long 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45865</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Change everything"? : the economy for the common good’s impacts on companies and communities and the potentials for regional development</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45862</link>
      <description>"Change everything"? : the economy for the common good’s impacts on companies and communities and the potentials for regional development - Sophia Roland 1992-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45862</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marine operators’ perception towards the new proposed environmental regulation : a case study of Svalbard, Norway</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45861</link>
      <description>Marine operators’ perception towards the new proposed environmental regulation : a case study of Svalbard, Norway - Carol Lopez 1975-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45861</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help the kelp : a cost-effectiveness analysis of large-scale kelp forest restoration efforts in the Arctic Archipelagos</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45863</link>
      <description>Help the kelp : a cost-effectiveness analysis of large-scale kelp forest restoration efforts in the Arctic Archipelagos - Eyð Maritudóttir Grønadal 1991-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45863</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the effectiveness of the marine protected area network in the Bay of Biscay</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45864</link>
      <description>Improving the effectiveness of the marine protected area network in the Bay of Biscay - Angelica Bas Gomez 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45864</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effects of water quality on the growth of lumpfish (Cyclopterus lumpus)</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45868</link>
      <description>The effects of water quality on the growth of lumpfish (Cyclopterus lumpus) - Amber Christina Monroe 1992-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45868</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Missing data and multiple imputation: A sampling study with the SAGA cohort</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45867</link>
      <description>Missing data and multiple imputation: A sampling study with the SAGA cohort - Marín Dögg Bjarnadóttir 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45867</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
