<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>skemman.is</title>
    <link>http://skemman.is</link>
    <description>Ritgerðir birtar á skemman.is</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>is</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 14:00:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Tuberculosis vaccination coverage and risk factors for incomplete vaccination among children five years and younger in the Manica and Sofala provinces of Mozambique</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44741</link>
      <description>Tuberculosis vaccination coverage and risk factors for incomplete vaccination among children five years and younger in the Manica and Sofala provinces of Mozambique - Marissa Wan Lynn Tousey-Pfarrer 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44741</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tengsl útundanótta við sálfélagslegar breytur: Hlutverk félagslegs samanburðar og þarfarinnar fyrir að tilheyra</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44743</link>
      <description>Tengsl útundanótta við sálfélagslegar breytur: Hlutverk félagslegs samanburðar og þarfarinnar fyrir að tilheyra - Kolbrún Jónsdóttir 1986-; Agnes Hekla Árnadóttir 1992-; Agnes Sigurðardóttir 1978-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44743</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative life cycle assessment of hydrogen production in Iceland and the EU-27</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44747</link>
      <description>Comparative life cycle assessment of hydrogen production in Iceland and the EU-27 - Drew Jacob Barron 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adolescents who struggle with substance use following domestic violence in their childhood</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44744</link>
      <description>Adolescents who struggle with substance use following domestic violence in their childhood - Birna Lind Pálmadóttir 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44744</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Examining gratitude in children and youth with disabilities : is there a difference between children and youth with motor disabilities and intellectual disabilities?</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44746</link>
      <description>Examining gratitude in children and youth with disabilities : is there a difference between children and youth with motor disabilities and intellectual disabilities? - Kara Björk Sævarsdóttir 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44746</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gender and performance anxiety in upper secondary dual-career sports programs in Iceland.</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44757</link>
      <description>Gender and performance anxiety in upper secondary dual-career sports programs in Iceland. - Þórey Björk Eyþórsdóttir 2001-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44757</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Icelandic startups dream of project management? : exploring the experience of participants in Icelandic business accelerators</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44752</link>
      <description>Do Icelandic startups dream of project management? : exploring the experience of participants in Icelandic business accelerators - Jóhannes Ingi Árnason 1982-; Sigrún Inga Kristinsdóttir 1971-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44752</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Örmögnun og vinnutengt þunglyndi: Aðgreining á grundvelli ólíkra áhrifaþátta</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44742</link>
      <description>Örmögnun og vinnutengt þunglyndi: Aðgreining á grundvelli ólíkra áhrifaþátta - Melkorka Arnarsdóttir 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44742</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The association of ADHD and self-esteem among university students</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44745</link>
      <description>The association of ADHD and self-esteem among university students - Guðrún Ýr Bjarnadóttir 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44745</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effects of different parenting styles on self-esteem</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44753</link>
      <description>The effects of different parenting styles on self-esteem - Rakel Guðjónsdóttir 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44753</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Usage and attitudes toward pornography among young adults in Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44751</link>
      <description>Usage and attitudes toward pornography among young adults in Iceland - Ingunn Eva Reynisdóttir 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44751</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sjálfbær stjórnun : mat á upplýsingagjöf og stjórnarháttum fyrirtækja​</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44750</link>
      <description>Sjálfbær stjórnun : mat á upplýsingagjöf og stjórnarháttum fyrirtækja​ - Kristín Ösp Þorleifsdóttir 1979-; Rósa Guðrún Erlingsdóttir 1970-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44750</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taugungamyndun í fullorðnum spendýrum: Fræðilegt yfirlit</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44755</link>
      <description>Taugungamyndun í fullorðnum spendýrum: Fræðilegt yfirlit - Jón Tryggvi Sigurþórsson 1986-; Björgúlfur Kristófer Sigurðsson 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44755</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating venture capital : an examination of strategies, decisions, and models</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44748</link>
      <description>Navigating venture capital : an examination of strategies, decisions, and models - Stefán Jónsson 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44748</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Viðhorf nýlegra útskrifaðra ljósmæðra til eðlilegra fæðinga og verndun þeirra á Fæðingarvakt Landspítala: Eigindlega viðtalsrannsókn</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44758</link>
      <description>Viðhorf nýlegra útskrifaðra ljósmæðra til eðlilegra fæðinga og verndun þeirra á Fæðingarvakt Landspítala: Eigindlega viðtalsrannsókn - Sunna Líf Guðmundsdóttir 1989-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hverjar eru ástæður þess að hraustum nýburum er gefin ábót á fyrstu viku eftir fæðingu á sjúkrahúsi og hvaða leiðir eru til úrbóta? Kerfisbundin fræðileg samantekt</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44759</link>
      <description>Hverjar eru ástæður þess að hraustum nýburum er gefin ábót á fyrstu viku eftir fæðingu á sjúkrahúsi og hvaða leiðir eru til úrbóta? Kerfisbundin fræðileg samantekt - Tinna Halldórsdóttir 1982-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44759</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mental toughness in Icelandic female football players : comparisons of the national team, top and second top women's divisions</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44761</link>
      <description>Mental toughness in Icelandic female football players : comparisons of the national team, top and second top women's divisions - Dagrún Birta Karlsdóttir 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of school-based light intervention on daytime napping and daytime sleepiness among adolescents in Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44762</link>
      <description>Effects of school-based light intervention on daytime napping and daytime sleepiness among adolescents in Iceland - Ingibjörg Patricia Magnúsdóttir 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44762</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stillbirth and trauma associated sleep disturbances: A population-based study of 27,605 women</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44749</link>
      <description>Stillbirth and trauma associated sleep disturbances: A population-based study of 27,605 women - Marsibil Ósk Helgadóttir 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44749</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tilgangur : rekstrarafleiðingar í hluta- og einkahlutafélögum þegar teknar eru ákvarðanir andstætt skráðum tilgangi</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44763</link>
      <description>Tilgangur : rekstrarafleiðingar í hluta- og einkahlutafélögum þegar teknar eru ákvarðanir andstætt skráðum tilgangi - Vilhelmína Ómarsdóttir 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44763</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The importance of social support in times of COVID-19 and its protective factor for adolescents’ anxiety</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44760</link>
      <description>The importance of social support in times of COVID-19 and its protective factor for adolescents’ anxiety - Sæunn Ýr Óskarsdóttir 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44760</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge and attitudes toward electroconvulsive therapy (ECT) among mental health workers and the public in Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44766</link>
      <description>Knowledge and attitudes toward electroconvulsive therapy (ECT) among mental health workers and the public in Iceland - Díana Sif Ingadóttir 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44766</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-esteem as a mediator of the effects of parental involvement on anxiety and depression</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44765</link>
      <description>Self-esteem as a mediator of the effects of parental involvement on anxiety and depression - Kolfinna Pétursdóttir 2001-; Steinþór Örn Helgason 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44765</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risk management and value creation : an international high-tech manufacturing company´s approach to risk management and value creation in new product development projects</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44764</link>
      <description>Risk management and value creation : an international high-tech manufacturing company´s approach to risk management and value creation in new product development projects - Eyjólfur Alexandersson 1981-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44764</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heilsueflandi útkomur í ljósmæðraþjónustu á Íslandi. Þróun og forprófun á útkomubreytum í fæðingu</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44754</link>
      <description>Heilsueflandi útkomur í ljósmæðraþjónustu á Íslandi. Þróun og forprófun á útkomubreytum í fæðingu - Ilmur Sól Eiríksdóttir 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/44754</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
