<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>skemman.is</title>
    <link>http://skemman.is</link>
    <description>Ritgerðir birtar á skemman.is</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>is</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 12:00:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>The Potential for Using Spruce (Picea) in Icelandic Forestry</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43327</link>
      <description>The Potential for Using Spruce (Picea) in Icelandic Forestry - Mai Lynn Duong 1989-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43327</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards a carbon neutral Vestmannaeyjar. Comparison of alternative fuels for backup district heating of Vestmannaeyjar.</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43328</link>
      <description>Towards a carbon neutral Vestmannaeyjar. Comparison of alternative fuels for backup district heating of Vestmannaeyjar. - Christian Michael Barrera 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43328</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glaciovolcanic edifices. Correlation of passage zone with ice sheet slope at Bláfjall tuya, NE-Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43329</link>
      <description>Glaciovolcanic edifices. Correlation of passage zone with ice sheet slope at Bláfjall tuya, NE-Iceland - Anna Margrét Sigurbergsdóttir 1989-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43329</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maturing of pre-expanded polystyrene - Effects of heat on maturing time and material strength</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43330</link>
      <description>Maturing of pre-expanded polystyrene - Effects of heat on maturing time and material strength - Jóhann Ingi Harðarson 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43330</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Playing hide and seek underwater: Evidence of orca (Orcinus orca) presence in offshore Icelandic waters through acoustic analysis</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43323</link>
      <description>Playing hide and seek underwater: Evidence of orca (Orcinus orca) presence in offshore Icelandic waters through acoustic analysis - Giulia Bellon 1992-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43323</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teacher Well-being and Functionality of Educational Models : a Study of Icelandic Playschools</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43326</link>
      <description>Teacher Well-being and Functionality of Educational Models : a Study of Icelandic Playschools - Nora Elisabeth Christine Jacob 1984-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of Injection-Induced Cooling using Tracer Test Data in the Hellisheiði Geothermal Field, SW-Iceland  Comparison of Numerical and Analytical Modelling Approaches</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43321</link>
      <description>Prediction of Injection-Induced Cooling using Tracer Test Data in the Hellisheiði Geothermal Field, SW-Iceland  Comparison of Numerical and Analytical Modelling Approaches - Teka Nigussie Gebru 1986-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43321</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Fluid Dynamics Simulation of a Box Designed to Ventilate Water Mist</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43322</link>
      <description>Computational Fluid Dynamics Simulation of a Box Designed to Ventilate Water Mist - Hafþór Helgi Heiðarsson 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43322</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microbial contamination in PUR- and PE- insulated fish tubs</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43325</link>
      <description>Microbial contamination in PUR- and PE- insulated fish tubs - Þóroddur Sigurðsson 1982-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43325</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abstractive Text Summarization for Icelandic</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43324</link>
      <description>Abstractive Text Summarization for Icelandic - Þór Sverrisson 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43324</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Children’s Yale-Brown Obsessive-Compulsive Scale: Factor analytic evaluation and literature review</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43320</link>
      <description>The Children’s Yale-Brown Obsessive-Compulsive Scale: Factor analytic evaluation and literature review - Bergrós Skúladóttir 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43320</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementation and testing of a novel and customizable digital health platform and study on automatic medication dispensers in Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43317</link>
      <description>Implementation and testing of a novel and customizable digital health platform and study on automatic medication dispensers in Iceland - María Kjartansdóttir 1991-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting early-stage Parkinson’s disease using virtual reality and biomedical parameters</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43318</link>
      <description>Predicting early-stage Parkinson’s disease using virtual reality and biomedical parameters - Þorbjörg Ída Ívarsdóttir 1990-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43318</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards a quantitative assessment of early-stage Parkinson’s disease using BioVRSea paradigm</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43319</link>
      <description>Towards a quantitative assessment of early-stage Parkinson’s disease using BioVRSea paradigm - Sigrún Anna Auðardóttir 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43319</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Íslensk þýðing og staðfærsla RAASI matslistans: Próffræðilegir eiginleikar og aldursviðmið</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43315</link>
      <description>Íslensk þýðing og staðfærsla RAASI matslistans: Próffræðilegir eiginleikar og aldursviðmið - Hulda Þórunn O. Þóroddsdóttir 1998-; Ingibjörg Jóna G. Björnsdóttir 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43315</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulation and analysis of inbound baggage handling at Keflavík Airport</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43316</link>
      <description>Simulation and analysis of inbound baggage handling at Keflavík Airport - Kristinn Ingi Guðjónsson 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43316</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hjónabandssæla - Athugun á próffræðilegum eiginleikum matskvarða sem mæla ánægju í parsamböndum í íslensku úrtaki</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43313</link>
      <description>Hjónabandssæla - Athugun á próffræðilegum eiginleikum matskvarða sem mæla ánægju í parsamböndum í íslensku úrtaki - Viktor Snær Rúnarsson 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43313</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting football match outcomes with fantasy league data and deep learning</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43314</link>
      <description>Predicting football match outcomes with fantasy league data and deep learning - Sveinn Henrik Kristinsson 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43314</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Markvissar upphitunaræfingar fyrir unglingsstúlkur í handbolta : notendavæn kennslumyndbönd fyrir þjálfara og iðkendur</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43307</link>
      <description>Markvissar upphitunaræfingar fyrir unglingsstúlkur í handbolta : notendavæn kennslumyndbönd fyrir þjálfara og iðkendur - Þóra María Sigurjónsdóttir 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43307</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why should you carbon offset your flights? An analysis of people’s willingness to pay for carbon offset and thereby offset the carbon footprints of flying.</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43311</link>
      <description>Why should you carbon offset your flights? An analysis of people’s willingness to pay for carbon offset and thereby offset the carbon footprints of flying. - Andrea Hanna Þorsteinsdóttir 1987-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43311</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corona crisis effects on Icelandic sport clubs in terms of human resource, finance and structural capacity</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43309</link>
      <description>Corona crisis effects on Icelandic sport clubs in terms of human resource, finance and structural capacity - Kolbrún Helga Hansen 1992-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43309</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automatic behavior classification of aquatic animals in underwater videos</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43310</link>
      <description>Automatic behavior classification of aquatic animals in underwater videos - Orri Steinn Guðfinnsson 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43310</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imbalanced learning in AML</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43308</link>
      <description>Imbalanced learning in AML - Steinar Ágúst Steinarsson 1992-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovative Digitalization and Agile Project Management: Icelandair’s “Maintener” Software Experience</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43312</link>
      <description>Innovative Digitalization and Agile Project Management: Icelandair’s “Maintener” Software Experience - Júlía Helgadóttir 1980-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43312</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ómeðhöndluð áföll í tengslum við ofbeldi og vanrækslu</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43301</link>
      <description>Ómeðhöndluð áföll í tengslum við ofbeldi og vanrækslu - Kristbjörg Eva Andersen Ramos 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43301</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
