<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>skemman.is</title>
    <link>http://skemman.is</link>
    <description>Ritgerðir birtar á skemman.is</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>is</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 12:00:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Origin of gabbro and anorthosite mineral clusters in Fagradalsfjall lavas</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43340</link>
      <description>Origin of gabbro and anorthosite mineral clusters in Fagradalsfjall lavas - William Charles Wenrich 1991-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43340</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Líðan háskólanema skoðuð út frá samtvinnun mismunabreyta: Áhrif hinseginleika, uppruna, búsetu og aldurs</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43341</link>
      <description>Líðan háskólanema skoðuð út frá samtvinnun mismunabreyta: Áhrif hinseginleika, uppruna, búsetu og aldurs - Laufey Ósk Jónsdóttir 2000-; Snædís Glóð Vikarsdóttir 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43341</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Traduzione in islandese di quattro novelle di Italo Calvino</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43339</link>
      <description>Traduzione in islandese di quattro novelle di Italo Calvino - Magnús Hinrik Guðjónsson 1954-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Segmentation of the Brainstem Substructures from MRI Using a Deep Learning Approach</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43342</link>
      <description>Automatic Segmentation of the Brainstem Substructures from MRI Using a Deep Learning Approach - Magnús Magnússon 1992-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43342</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Footprints in the Nordics:  Do dietary choices of Nordic households affect their consumption-based carbon footprints?</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43333</link>
      <description>Carbon Footprints in the Nordics:  Do dietary choices of Nordic households affect their consumption-based carbon footprints? - Húbert Óðinn Huntingdon-Williams 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43333</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards a carbon neutral Vestmannaeyjar. Comparison of alternative fuels for backup district heating of Vestmannaeyjar.</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43328</link>
      <description>Towards a carbon neutral Vestmannaeyjar. Comparison of alternative fuels for backup district heating of Vestmannaeyjar. - Christian Michael Barrera 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43328</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maturing of pre-expanded polystyrene - Effects of heat on maturing time and material strength</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43330</link>
      <description>Maturing of pre-expanded polystyrene - Effects of heat on maturing time and material strength - Jóhann Ingi Harðarson 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43330</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vatnajökull surface mass balance - a weighted linear regression model</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43332</link>
      <description>Vatnajökull surface mass balance - a weighted linear regression model - Marta Björgvinsdóttir 1987-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43332</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glaciovolcanic edifices. Correlation of passage zone with ice sheet slope at Bláfjall tuya, NE-Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43329</link>
      <description>Glaciovolcanic edifices. Correlation of passage zone with ice sheet slope at Bláfjall tuya, NE-Iceland - Anna Margrét Sigurbergsdóttir 1989-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43329</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Endurhönnun á töppunarskörungslöpp fyrir Elkem ísland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43331</link>
      <description>Endurhönnun á töppunarskörungslöpp fyrir Elkem ísland - Hafsteinn Einar Ágústsson 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43331</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stigskipt Bayesískt líkan fyrir íslenskan fiskuppboðsmarkað</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43336</link>
      <description>Stigskipt Bayesískt líkan fyrir íslenskan fiskuppboðsmarkað - Sólveig Ástudóttir Daðadóttir 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polygenic risk scores using the lasso in a multi-cohort setting with application for lipoprotein(a)</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43337</link>
      <description>Polygenic risk scores using the lasso in a multi-cohort setting with application for lipoprotein(a) - Steinþór Árdal 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43337</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Potential for Using Spruce (Picea) in Icelandic Forestry</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43327</link>
      <description>The Potential for Using Spruce (Picea) in Icelandic Forestry - Mai Lynn Duong 1989-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43327</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temperature and salinity of the deep geothermal fluid in the Reykjanes geothermal field based on fluid inclusions</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43338</link>
      <description>Temperature and salinity of the deep geothermal fluid in the Reykjanes geothermal field based on fluid inclusions - Linus Huene 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43338</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of conditional discrimination skills and establishment of identity matching using within-stimulus prompts while ensuring motivation</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43334</link>
      <description>Evaluation of conditional discrimination skills and establishment of identity matching using within-stimulus prompts while ensuring motivation - Lena Egilsdóttir 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training staff in a secure psychiatric unit to set boundaries and communicate empathetically with patients</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43335</link>
      <description>Training staff in a secure psychiatric unit to set boundaries and communicate empathetically with patients - Margrét G. Kristjánsson 1990-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43335</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Playing hide and seek underwater: Evidence of orca (Orcinus orca) presence in offshore Icelandic waters through acoustic analysis</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43323</link>
      <description>Playing hide and seek underwater: Evidence of orca (Orcinus orca) presence in offshore Icelandic waters through acoustic analysis - Giulia Bellon 1992-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43323</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teacher Well-being and Functionality of Educational Models : a Study of Icelandic Playschools</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43326</link>
      <description>Teacher Well-being and Functionality of Educational Models : a Study of Icelandic Playschools - Nora Elisabeth Christine Jacob 1984-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of Injection-Induced Cooling using Tracer Test Data in the Hellisheiði Geothermal Field, SW-Iceland  Comparison of Numerical and Analytical Modelling Approaches</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43321</link>
      <description>Prediction of Injection-Induced Cooling using Tracer Test Data in the Hellisheiði Geothermal Field, SW-Iceland  Comparison of Numerical and Analytical Modelling Approaches - Teka Nigussie Gebru 1986-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43321</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Fluid Dynamics Simulation of a Box Designed to Ventilate Water Mist</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43322</link>
      <description>Computational Fluid Dynamics Simulation of a Box Designed to Ventilate Water Mist - Hafþór Helgi Heiðarsson 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43322</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microbial contamination in PUR- and PE- insulated fish tubs</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43325</link>
      <description>Microbial contamination in PUR- and PE- insulated fish tubs - Þóroddur Sigurðsson 1982-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43325</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abstractive Text Summarization for Icelandic</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43324</link>
      <description>Abstractive Text Summarization for Icelandic - Þór Sverrisson 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43324</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Children’s Yale-Brown Obsessive-Compulsive Scale: Factor analytic evaluation and literature review</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43320</link>
      <description>The Children’s Yale-Brown Obsessive-Compulsive Scale: Factor analytic evaluation and literature review - Bergrós Skúladóttir 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43320</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementation and testing of a novel and customizable digital health platform and study on automatic medication dispensers in Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43317</link>
      <description>Implementation and testing of a novel and customizable digital health platform and study on automatic medication dispensers in Iceland - María Kjartansdóttir 1991-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting early-stage Parkinson’s disease using virtual reality and biomedical parameters</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43318</link>
      <description>Predicting early-stage Parkinson’s disease using virtual reality and biomedical parameters - Þorbjörg Ída Ívarsdóttir 1990-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/43318</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
