<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>skemman.is</title>
    <link>http://skemman.is</link>
    <description>Ritgerðir birtar á skemman.is</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>is</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 17:05:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>The finngálkn: A review of literary sources from the 12th century to the 18th century</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51584</link>
      <description>The finngálkn: A review of literary sources from the 12th century to the 18th century - Dante Abel 1990-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51584</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home for kin or career? : exploring return migration of Icelandic citizens</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51588</link>
      <description>Home for kin or career? : exploring return migration of Icelandic citizens - Hjördís Guðmundsdóttir 1984-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51588</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Áhrif vanrækslu í æsku á fæðuvenjur fullorðinna kvenna á Íslandi. Áfallasaga kvenna.</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51585</link>
      <description>Áhrif vanrækslu í æsku á fæðuvenjur fullorðinna kvenna á Íslandi. Áfallasaga kvenna. - Ósk Matthildur Arnarsdóttir 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51585</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tækifæri til nýsköpunar: Að skapa aðgengilega fræðslu fyrir fatlað fólk</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51586</link>
      <description>Tækifæri til nýsköpunar: Að skapa aðgengilega fræðslu fyrir fatlað fólk - Sif Maríudóttir 1991-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51586</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Azithromycin on kidney cells in culture treated with and without 2,8-Dihydroxyadenine crystals</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51582</link>
      <description>Effects of Azithromycin on kidney cells in culture treated with and without 2,8-Dihydroxyadenine crystals - Elsa Karen Sighvatsdóttir 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51582</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Unknown Motion: The Performance and Practice of Divination and Prophecy Rituals in the Sagas of Icelanders</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51583</link>
      <description>The Unknown Motion: The Performance and Practice of Divination and Prophecy Rituals in the Sagas of Icelanders - Ariya Theprangsimankul 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51583</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hlutleysi löggiltra fasteigna- og skipasala</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51580</link>
      <description>Hlutleysi löggiltra fasteigna- og skipasala - Jóna Rún Svavarsdóttir 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51580</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Málamyndahjúskapur í íslenskum rétti : túlkun og beiting 1. og 2. mgr. 92. gr., sbr. 8. mgr. 70. gr. laga um útlendinga nr. 80/2016 með hliðsjón af EES-rétti</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51579</link>
      <description>Málamyndahjúskapur í íslenskum rétti : túlkun og beiting 1. og 2. mgr. 92. gr., sbr. 8. mgr. 70. gr. laga um útlendinga nr. 80/2016 með hliðsjón af EES-rétti - Angelika Hilla 2001-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51579</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lágmarks verndarráðstafanir 18. gr. flokkunarreglugerðarinnar : hvernig uppfylla íslensk fjármálafyrirtæki skilyrði ákvæðisins?</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51581</link>
      <description>Lágmarks verndarráðstafanir 18. gr. flokkunarreglugerðarinnar : hvernig uppfylla íslensk fjármálafyrirtæki skilyrði ákvæðisins? - Iðunn Helgadóttir 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51581</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skipulögð brotastarfsemi : réttargrundvöllur, helstu frumbrot, úrræði yfirvalda og dómaframkvæmd</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51578</link>
      <description>Skipulögð brotastarfsemi : réttargrundvöllur, helstu frumbrot, úrræði yfirvalda og dómaframkvæmd - Ingibjörg Austmann Ingadóttir 1991-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51578</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>El castellano como lengua global: Su lugar en un mundo de linguae francae</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51577</link>
      <description>El castellano como lengua global: Su lugar en un mundo de linguae francae - Javier Hualde 1983-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51577</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notkun lyfjabrunna við skuggaefnisgjöf með vélsprautu í tölvusneiðmyndatöku á Landspítala: Samanburðarrannsókn, upplifun sjúklinga og verklagstillaga</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51571</link>
      <description>Notkun lyfjabrunna við skuggaefnisgjöf með vélsprautu í tölvusneiðmyndatöku á Landspítala: Samanburðarrannsókn, upplifun sjúklinga og verklagstillaga - Þóra Björk Stefánsdóttir 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51571</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring fish size, otolith characteristics, gonadosomatic index (GSI), and hepatosomatic index (HSI) of six eelpout species (Lycodes spp.) in Icelandic waters</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51573</link>
      <description>Exploring fish size, otolith characteristics, gonadosomatic index (GSI), and hepatosomatic index (HSI) of six eelpout species (Lycodes spp.) in Icelandic waters - Bradley, Alexis Jane, 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51573</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Art brings people together” :  bridging knowledge systems through Labrador Inuit art and craft to support equitable environmental research in Nunatsiavut</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51574</link>
      <description>“Art brings people together” :  bridging knowledge systems through Labrador Inuit art and craft to support equitable environmental research in Nunatsiavut - Steele, Jessica, 1992-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51574</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effects of anthropogenic materials and activities on bird diversity along the West Coast of Michigan</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51572</link>
      <description>The effects of anthropogenic materials and activities on bird diversity along the West Coast of Michigan - Peters, Justine, 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51572</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PFAS efni í brjóstamjólk og blóði íslenskra kvenna</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51575</link>
      <description>PFAS efni í brjóstamjólk og blóði íslenskra kvenna - Sunneva Halldórsdóttir 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51575</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Áhrif vatnatilskipunarinnar á vatnsaflsvirkjanir og skyldur aðildarríkja við leyfisveitingar</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51570</link>
      <description>Áhrif vatnatilskipunarinnar á vatnsaflsvirkjanir og skyldur aðildarríkja við leyfisveitingar - Rúnar Bergþórsson 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51570</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The fjords of the ringed seal : assessing the status of ringed seals in western Svalbard through machine learning</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51576</link>
      <description>The fjords of the ringed seal : assessing the status of ringed seals in western Svalbard through machine learning - Sastre, Alberto Roldán, 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51576</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cover preference of salamanders within the forests and wetlands of the Western Coast of Michigan</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51568</link>
      <description>Cover preference of salamanders within the forests and wetlands of the Western Coast of Michigan - Brown, Vladimir Michael, 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51568</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fishing for plastics : the socio-economic impacts of marine plastic pollution on small-scale fisheries in the Mediterranean Sea</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51569</link>
      <description>Fishing for plastics : the socio-economic impacts of marine plastic pollution on small-scale fisheries in the Mediterranean Sea - Horváth, Borbála Kinga  1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51569</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Survival of zooplankton communities in ships’ ballast water tanks</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51566</link>
      <description>Survival of zooplankton communities in ships’ ballast water tanks - Kieckhöfel, Tobias Phil, 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51566</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gone skipping : understanding intermittent breeding in Atlantic puffins in Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51567</link>
      <description>Gone skipping : understanding intermittent breeding in Atlantic puffins in Iceland - Teperi, Anni Laura Maria, 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51567</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Digital Wellbeing Interventions on Employee Mental Health and Workplace Outcomes: A Systematic Review</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51565</link>
      <description>The Impact of Digital Wellbeing Interventions on Employee Mental Health and Workplace Outcomes: A Systematic Review - Heiða Ósk Guðmundsdóttir 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51565</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the association two large effect loci vgll3 and six6 have on the maturation timing in Wild Atlantic salmon</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51564</link>
      <description>Investigating the association two large effect loci vgll3 and six6 have on the maturation timing in Wild Atlantic salmon - Ainsworth, Sadie Jeanne 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51564</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Af hverju lýðveldi? : hugmyndir, áhrif og ágreiningur við lýðveldisstofnun Íslands</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51562</link>
      <description>Af hverju lýðveldi? : hugmyndir, áhrif og ágreiningur við lýðveldisstofnun Íslands - Eyþór Möller Árnason 1992-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/51562</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
