<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>skemman.is</title>
    <link>http://skemman.is</link>
    <description>Ritgerðir birtar á skemman.is</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>is</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 11:05:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Human Impacts on Fossvogur Bay (Reykjavík, Iceland): Analysis of a Sediment Core</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49132</link>
      <description>Human Impacts on Fossvogur Bay (Reykjavík, Iceland): Analysis of a Sediment Core - Stína Malen Sigurveigardóttir 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skewing the Extraction of Emotional Expression From a Group of Faces With Memory Matching Tasks. A study on Visual Working Memory and Ensemble Perception</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49131</link>
      <description>Skewing the Extraction of Emotional Expression From a Group of Faces With Memory Matching Tasks. A study on Visual Working Memory and Ensemble Perception - Hrönn Júlía Stefánsdóttir 2002-; Sigríður Helga Kárdal Ásgeirsdóttir 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49131</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Capacities defined by pluricomplex extremal functions</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49133</link>
      <description>Capacities defined by pluricomplex extremal functions - Tryggvi Kalman Jónsson 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jarðvarmavirkjanir og mótun ferðamannastaða.                     Tilviksrannsókn: Þeistareykir á Norðurlandi eystra.</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49124</link>
      <description>Jarðvarmavirkjanir og mótun ferðamannastaða.                     Tilviksrannsókn: Þeistareykir á Norðurlandi eystra. - Sigríður Kristín Jónasdóttir 1960-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49124</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teachers’ Attitudes Towards  Inclusive Education: A Qualitative Study in a Chinese Elementary School Based on Critical Disability Theory</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49127</link>
      <description>Teachers’ Attitudes Towards  Inclusive Education: A Qualitative Study in a Chinese Elementary School Based on Critical Disability Theory - Zhijing Deng 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49127</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notkun nikótínpúða í náinni framtíð: Þróun nikótínpúða á Íslandi og framtíðaráskoranir á markaðnum</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49126</link>
      <description>Notkun nikótínpúða í náinni framtíð: Þróun nikótínpúða á Íslandi og framtíðaráskoranir á markaðnum - Kolfinna Ólafsdóttir 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49126</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Losun bakvatns hitaveitu á höfuðborgarsvæðinu: Greining á núverandi kerfi og kostnaðargreining á losun</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49125</link>
      <description>Losun bakvatns hitaveitu á höfuðborgarsvæðinu: Greining á núverandi kerfi og kostnaðargreining á losun - Ragnheiður Ingólfsdóttir 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49125</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In vivo analysis of proteasome function, location and transport in Drosophila melanogaster motor neurons.</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49128</link>
      <description>In vivo analysis of proteasome function, location and transport in Drosophila melanogaster motor neurons. - Ólavía Guðrún Gísladóttir 2002-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49128</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tölfræðilíkön fyrir mæliskekkju byggð á Bayesískum stigskiptum Gaussískum líkönum</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49130</link>
      <description>Tölfræðilíkön fyrir mæliskekkju byggð á Bayesískum stigskiptum Gaussískum líkönum - Rafael Daníel Vias 1990-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49130</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Speech Technology Integration in Children’s Reading Education: A Study of TTS and STT Implementation in an Icelandic Educational Game</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49129</link>
      <description>Evaluating Speech Technology Integration in Children’s Reading Education: A Study of TTS and STT Implementation in an Icelandic Educational Game - Alexander Guðmundsson 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49129</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Actuarial Assumptions: Mortality Modeling and Demographic Analysis for Stapi Pension Fund</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49117</link>
      <description>Evaluating Actuarial Assumptions: Mortality Modeling and Demographic Analysis for Stapi Pension Fund - Anna Karen Kristinsdóttir 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49117</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stofnrannsókn á hagamúsum Apodemus sylvaticus yfir tímgunartímabil í tveimur vistgerðum</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49116</link>
      <description>Stofnrannsókn á hagamúsum Apodemus sylvaticus yfir tímgunartímabil í tveimur vistgerðum - Sólmundur Örn Jónsson 2001-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How has Security, Relations, and Regional alliances in South Asia been affected the return of the Taliban?así</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49114</link>
      <description>How has Security, Relations, and Regional alliances in South Asia been affected the return of the Taliban?así - Einar Kári Guðmundsson 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49114</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Fluid Dynamics Simulation of a Fluid Assisted Transfer System</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49115</link>
      <description>Computational Fluid Dynamics Simulation of a Fluid Assisted Transfer System - Birkir Jóhannes Ómarsson 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49115</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic graph neural networks for credit risk modeling : a multi-modal approach to SME default prediction</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49120</link>
      <description>Dynamic graph neural networks for credit risk modeling : a multi-modal approach to SME default prediction - Halldór Kristinsson 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Icelandic insurance claims : from text to incident categories</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49121</link>
      <description>Understanding Icelandic insurance claims : from text to incident categories - Atli Egilsson 1992-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gender Differences in Emotional Expression: An Analysis of Blog Post Comments in Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49118</link>
      <description>Gender Differences in Emotional Expression: An Analysis of Blog Post Comments in Iceland - Prince Charles Stephens 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language models for classification of patient text messages</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49119</link>
      <description>Language models for classification of patient text messages - Kaustab Chandra Sahu 2000-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49119</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nýtt landslag íþrótta og stjórnmála. Hinar nýju áherslur Sádi-Arabíu í íþróttum</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49122</link>
      <description>Nýtt landslag íþrótta og stjórnmála. Hinar nýju áherslur Sádi-Arabíu í íþróttum - Samúel Ingi Daníelsson 2001-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Geospatial Modeling with Prithvi-EO-2.0: Development and Validation of a Foundation Model for Earth Observation</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49123</link>
      <description>Advancing Geospatial Modeling with Prithvi-EO-2.0: Development and Validation of a Foundation Model for Earth Observation - Þorsteinn Elí Gíslason 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Áskoranir og bjargir leikskólastjóra sem starfa við ungbarnaleikskóla</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49111</link>
      <description>Áskoranir og bjargir leikskólastjóra sem starfa við ungbarnaleikskóla - Jóna Rún Gísladóttir 1980-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49111</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bumblebee-plant interactions in urban green spaces in Reykjavik</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49112</link>
      <description>Bumblebee-plant interactions in urban green spaces in Reykjavik - Katja Schmela 1981-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49112</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sierra Leone Creole Language: Exploring the Influences of Sierra Leone Creole Language in English and Native Languages</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49113</link>
      <description>The Sierra Leone Creole Language: Exploring the Influences of Sierra Leone Creole Language in English and Native Languages - Doro Thoronka 1976-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49113</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heimalestur barna með lestrarvanda: Foreldrum kenndar aðferðir G-PALS með myndbandssýnikennslu</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49110</link>
      <description>Heimalestur barna með lestrarvanda: Foreldrum kenndar aðferðir G-PALS með myndbandssýnikennslu - Jónína Helga Ólafsdóttir 1968-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49110</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>„Að berjast við dreka“: Reynsla mæðra með geðsjúkdóma af móðurhlutverkinu</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49108</link>
      <description>„Að berjast við dreka“: Reynsla mæðra með geðsjúkdóma af móðurhlutverkinu - Áróra Huld Bjarnadóttir 1992-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/49108</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
