<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>skemman.is</title>
    <link>http://skemman.is</link>
    <description>Ritgerðir birtar á skemman.is</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>is</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 10:00:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Variation in shoaling behavior in lake Mývatn threespine stickleback in relation to temperature and origin</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45851</link>
      <description>Variation in shoaling behavior in lake Mývatn threespine stickleback in relation to temperature and origin - Spencer William Edwards 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45851</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benthic habitat mapping in offshore Qeqertarsuaq Tunua, West Greenland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45852</link>
      <description>Benthic habitat mapping in offshore Qeqertarsuaq Tunua, West Greenland - Joyce Mulder 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45852</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can sailing tourism and marine research benefit from each other? :  An arctic case study with particular focus on Iceland and Northern Norway</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45853</link>
      <description>Can sailing tourism and marine research benefit from each other? :  An arctic case study with particular focus on Iceland and Northern Norway - Hugo Vancraenenbroeck 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45853</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple stressor effects on morphology of Zostera marina, its erosion mitigation capacity and shoot dislodgement, in the Turku Archipelago, Finland.</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45854</link>
      <description>Multiple stressor effects on morphology of Zostera marina, its erosion mitigation capacity and shoot dislodgement, in the Turku Archipelago, Finland. - Riitta Maila Chorfi 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45854</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting course for sustainability : evaluating resident‘s perspectives of cruise tourism in Ísafjörður, Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45855</link>
      <description>Setting course for sustainability : evaluating resident‘s perspectives of cruise tourism in Ísafjörður, Iceland - Elizabeth Riendeau 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45855</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The non-silent world : acoustic responses of white-beaked dolphins (lagenorhynchus albirostris) to changes in maritime traffic : a case study during the covid-19 anthropause in Skjálfandi Bay, Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45856</link>
      <description>The non-silent world : acoustic responses of white-beaked dolphins (lagenorhynchus albirostris) to changes in maritime traffic : a case study during the covid-19 anthropause in Skjálfandi Bay, Iceland - Mathieu Reverberi 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45856</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marine litter as a vector for fouling species in the southwest, northeast, and Westfjords of Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45857</link>
      <description>Marine litter as a vector for fouling species in the southwest, northeast, and Westfjords of Iceland - Holly Athalie Solloway 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45857</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Próffræðilegir eiginleikar íslenskrar þýðingar Bergen vinnufíknikvarðans (BWAS)</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45850</link>
      <description>Próffræðilegir eiginleikar íslenskrar þýðingar Bergen vinnufíknikvarðans (BWAS) - Snædís Gígja Snorradóttir 1992-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45850</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Áhrif smithreinsunar á seytingu próteina við framlengda kuldageymslu blóðflöguþykknis</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45849</link>
      <description>Áhrif smithreinsunar á seytingu próteina við framlengda kuldageymslu blóðflöguþykknis - Ingibjörg Hjörleifsdóttir 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45849</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable futures: a case study of the implementation of sustainable business models in Icelandic energy companies and their relevance to sustainability transitions</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45848</link>
      <description>Sustainable futures: a case study of the implementation of sustainable business models in Icelandic energy companies and their relevance to sustainability transitions - Cary Kincaid Corcoran 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45848</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dysfunctional telomeres in BRCA2 deficient breast cell lines</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45847</link>
      <description>Dysfunctional telomeres in BRCA2 deficient breast cell lines - Alexander Örn Kárason 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45847</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Production, characterization &amp; bioactivity of lyophilized and spray dried platelet lysates from expired platelet concentrates</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45845</link>
      <description>Production, characterization &amp; bioactivity of lyophilized and spray dried platelet lysates from expired platelet concentrates - Kasper Bruun Lövenstein 1988-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45845</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mat á landgræðslu í Hítardal með Sentinel-2 gervitunglamyndum</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45846</link>
      <description>Mat á landgræðslu í Hítardal með Sentinel-2 gervitunglamyndum - Emil Snorri Árnason 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45846</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>„Ég held þú getir ekki lifað án þess að vera skapandi“ : mikilvægi sköpunar í kennslustofunni og lífinu sjálfu</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45837</link>
      <description>„Ég held þú getir ekki lifað án þess að vera skapandi“ : mikilvægi sköpunar í kennslustofunni og lífinu sjálfu - Ásthildur Ákadóttir 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45837</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian spatial modeling of carbon content in Icelandic soil using R-INLA</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45836</link>
      <description>Bayesian spatial modeling of carbon content in Icelandic soil using R-INLA - Gylfi Snær Sigurðsson 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45836</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>House of Care : a gate for integration and inclusion</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45838</link>
      <description>House of Care : a gate for integration and inclusion - Rami A. S. Mussa 1981-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45838</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ekki hræða, frekar ræða : vandamál og lausnir umhverfismenntunar, með tilliti til náttúrutenginga, sjálfbærni og samráðs</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45840</link>
      <description>Ekki hræða, frekar ræða : vandamál og lausnir umhverfismenntunar, með tilliti til náttúrutenginga, sjálfbærni og samráðs - Unnur Björnsdóttir 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45840</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leitin að týnda tónskáldinu : hvaða tækifæri felast í því að nota tónlist með mannkostamenntun að leiðarljósi?</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45842</link>
      <description>Leitin að týnda tónskáldinu : hvaða tækifæri felast í því að nota tónlist með mannkostamenntun að leiðarljósi? - Anna Halldórsdóttir 1970-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45842</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>„Ég hata ekki röddina mína lengur“ : söngkennsla til endurhæfingar og velferðar</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45841</link>
      <description>„Ég hata ekki röddina mína lengur“ : söngkennsla til endurhæfingar og velferðar - Sólrún Hedda Benedikz 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45841</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samfélag markar sér stað : landnám í gamla Vesturbænum</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45839</link>
      <description>Samfélag markar sér stað : landnám í gamla Vesturbænum - Magnea Guðrún Gunnarsdóttir 1979-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Viðhorf til kvenkyns tónskálda og lagahöfunda : frá Ethel Smyth til Bríetar</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45844</link>
      <description>Viðhorf til kvenkyns tónskálda og lagahöfunda : frá Ethel Smyth til Bríetar - Björk Ásgrímsdóttir 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45844</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silent Icelandicrete : Icelandic biomaterial research</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45843</link>
      <description>Silent Icelandicrete : Icelandic biomaterial research - Viltė Adomavičiūtė 1987-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45843</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Promise of Other Effective area-based Conservation Measures (OECM) to advance biodiversity conservation in Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45834</link>
      <description>The Promise of Other Effective area-based Conservation Measures (OECM) to advance biodiversity conservation in Iceland - Helga Hvanndal Björnsdóttir 1992-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45834</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The state of cybersecurity vulnerability reporting in Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45832</link>
      <description>The state of cybersecurity vulnerability reporting in Iceland - Þorsteinn Kristinn Ingólfsson 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45832</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Convergence of power series in several complex variables</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45833</link>
      <description>Convergence of power series in several complex variables - Arngunnur Einarsdóttir 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/45833</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
