<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>skemman.is</title>
    <link>http://skemman.is</link>
    <description>Ritgerðir birtar á skemman.is</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>is</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 13:02:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating humanitarian crises in armed conflict : exploring international legal frameworks and sovereignty dynamics with the Israel-Palestine conflict as a precedent</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47546</link>
      <description>Navigating humanitarian crises in armed conflict : exploring international legal frameworks and sovereignty dynamics with the Israel-Palestine conflict as a precedent - Donika Kolica 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47546</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heimildir lögreglu við rannsóknir á skipulagðri brotastarfsemi</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47548</link>
      <description>Heimildir lögreglu við rannsóknir á skipulagðri brotastarfsemi - Daldís Perla Magnúsdóttir 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47548</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transdiagnostic cognitive behavioural treatment for persistent physical symptoms that cause functional impairment and psychological distress : pilot randomised controlled trial</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47550</link>
      <description>Transdiagnostic cognitive behavioural treatment for persistent physical symptoms that cause functional impairment and psychological distress : pilot randomised controlled trial - Elín Broddadóttir 1992-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47550</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“No one listened to me for ten years” : the experience of people with fibromyalgia in seeking a diagnosis &amp; receiving appropriate help within primary health care in Iceland : a qualitative study</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47551</link>
      <description>“No one listened to me for ten years” : the experience of people with fibromyalgia in seeking a diagnosis &amp; receiving appropriate help within primary health care in Iceland : a qualitative study - Björg Hákonardóttir 1992-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47551</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Academic burnout : the relationship between academic burnout, perfectionism, and inflated responsibility</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47549</link>
      <description>Academic burnout : the relationship between academic burnout, perfectionism, and inflated responsibility - Jóhannes Geir H. Ólafsson 1992-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47549</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the effect of caregiver support on psychological distress in stem cell transplant patients</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47554</link>
      <description>Exploring the effect of caregiver support on psychological distress in stem cell transplant patients - Bjarki Jóhannsson 1991-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47554</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feasibility and efficacy of the parenting program : are you connecting? upbringing, attachment and the parenting role</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47552</link>
      <description>Feasibility and efficacy of the parenting program : are you connecting? upbringing, attachment and the parenting role - Sóley María Helgadóttir 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47552</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kúabelgir Uppskera og fóðurgildi einærra belgjurta fyrir mjólkurkýr</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47560</link>
      <description>Kúabelgir Uppskera og fóðurgildi einærra belgjurta fyrir mjólkurkýr - Helga Rún Jóhannsdóttir 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skattalegar afleiðingar við skiptingu félaga</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47555</link>
      <description>Skattalegar afleiðingar við skiptingu félaga - Skarphéðinn Vernharðsson 2001-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47555</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early detection of autism in primary healthcare in Iceland : parental experience of the procedure and services provided for toddlers, following a positive screening</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47556</link>
      <description>Early detection of autism in primary healthcare in Iceland : parental experience of the procedure and services provided for toddlers, following a positive screening - María Lovísa Breiðdal 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47556</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of new carbon dioxide degassing equipment in RAS</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47553</link>
      <description>Evaluation of new carbon dioxide degassing equipment in RAS - Sigurður Ívar Skúlason 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47553</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond words : qualitative study on survivors' experiences of the decision-making process of disclosing sexual violence on social media</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47557</link>
      <description>Beyond words : qualitative study on survivors' experiences of the decision-making process of disclosing sexual violence on social media - Alda Dís Arnardóttir 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47557</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effectiveness of a group based cognitive behavioural therapy for GAD at primary health care level : pilot study</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47558</link>
      <description>The effectiveness of a group based cognitive behavioural therapy for GAD at primary health care level : pilot study - Karen Geirsdóttir 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47558</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experiences of the legal system and impact on victims of sexual violence</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47561</link>
      <description>Experiences of the legal system and impact on victims of sexual violence - Hildur Hálfdánardóttir 1995-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47561</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adherence to aspirin treatment during pregnancy</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47562</link>
      <description>Adherence to aspirin treatment during pregnancy - Fanney Sigurgeirsdóttir 1988-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47562</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vopnaburður lögreglu : valdheimildir lögreglu í ljósi öryggis almennings og lögreglumanna</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47547</link>
      <description>Vopnaburður lögreglu : valdheimildir lögreglu í ljósi öryggis almennings og lögreglumanna - Inga Hrönn Ásgeirsdóttir 1990-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47547</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Býflugnarækt í borgarvistkerf - Leiðir og lausnir fyrir býflugnarækt í íslensku borgarumhverf</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47559</link>
      <description>Býflugnarækt í borgarvistkerf - Leiðir og lausnir fyrir býflugnarækt í íslensku borgarumhverf - Magnús Guðbergur Jónsson Núpan 1984-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uppgræðsla ofanflóðavarna: Skipulag, framkvæmd og árangur við endurheimt staðargróðurs</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47569</link>
      <description>Uppgræðsla ofanflóðavarna: Skipulag, framkvæmd og árangur við endurheimt staðargróðurs - Hulda Birna A Albertsdóttir 1982-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47569</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying Sphagnum spp. presence and  distribution along a gradient in aeolian  mineral deposition in Icelandic mires</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47571</link>
      <description>Quantifying Sphagnum spp. presence and  distribution along a gradient in aeolian  mineral deposition in Icelandic mires - Lorenzo Vegliò 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47571</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forsendur staðarvals matvöruverslana í Reykjavík. Markaðshagsmunir og sjálfbærnisjónarmið.</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47566</link>
      <description>Forsendur staðarvals matvöruverslana í Reykjavík. Markaðshagsmunir og sjálfbærnisjónarmið. - Díana Berglind Valbergsdóttir 1977-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47566</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brúin á Skeiðarársandi og önnur sérstæð útivistarsvæði</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47568</link>
      <description>Brúin á Skeiðarársandi og önnur sérstæð útivistarsvæði - Halldór Jón Björgvinsson 1977-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47568</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating a web-based cognitive behavioral therapy intervention for women experiencing infertility : a randomized controlled trial</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47563</link>
      <description>Evaluating a web-based cognitive behavioral therapy intervention for women experiencing infertility : a randomized controlled trial - Sigurbirna Hafliðadóttir 1978-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47563</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sleep revolution lifestyle study : a qualitative study of the participants’ experience</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47565</link>
      <description>Sleep revolution lifestyle study : a qualitative study of the participants’ experience - Wiktoria Marika Borowska 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47565</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thematic framework analysis of patients’ experience regarding gCBT for generalised anxiety disorder</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47567</link>
      <description>Thematic framework analysis of patients’ experience regarding gCBT for generalised anxiety disorder - Brynja Björk Beck Þórsdóttir 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47567</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effects of using a police case information portal on victims of sexual violence</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47564</link>
      <description>The effects of using a police case information portal on victims of sexual violence - Karítas Lára Rafnkelsdóttir 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/47564</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
