<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>skemman.is</title>
    <link>http://skemman.is</link>
    <description>Ritgerðir birtar á skemman.is</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>is</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 17:00:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Zebrafish model of ADHD : analysis of metabolomic and lipidomic pathways</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46302</link>
      <description>Zebrafish model of ADHD : analysis of metabolomic and lipidomic pathways - Brynja Rún Sævarsdóttir 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46302</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modelling the conductive characteristics of the human lower back using medical imaging and FEM modelling to optimize tSCS therapy</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46303</link>
      <description>Modelling the conductive characteristics of the human lower back using medical imaging and FEM modelling to optimize tSCS therapy - Jón Andri Árnason 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46303</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effect of endothelial cells on pancreatic spheroid phenotype and chemoresistance</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46304</link>
      <description>The effect of endothelial cells on pancreatic spheroid phenotype and chemoresistance - Tryggvi Helmutsson 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46304</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Að „höndla" áfengi og að höndla með áfengi</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46300</link>
      <description>Að „höndla" áfengi og að höndla með áfengi - Þormóður Þormóðsson 2001-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46300</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business plan for opening a surf camp in Iceland</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46301</link>
      <description>Business plan for opening a surf camp in Iceland - Einar Sveinn Pálsson 1996-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Undireiningar próteasóma: Undirbúningur fyrir flúrmerkingar þriggja undireininga próteasóma í D.melanogaster</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46299</link>
      <description>Undireiningar próteasóma: Undirbúningur fyrir flúrmerkingar þriggja undireininga próteasóma í D.melanogaster - Elísabet Guðmundsdóttir 2001-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Öryggi barna í innkaupakerru - Minni kerra meira öryggi?</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46297</link>
      <description>Öryggi barna í innkaupakerru - Minni kerra meira öryggi? - Aron Ingi Sveinsson 1996-; Elín Ósk Jónasdóttir 1996-; Kristin Orradóttir 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46297</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Additive functionals with product toll functions on Galton-Watson trees</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46298</link>
      <description>Additive functionals with product toll functions on Galton-Watson trees - Guðjón Helgi Auðunsson 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dental procedures in children done under general anesthesia in 2004-2017</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46290</link>
      <description>Dental procedures in children done under general anesthesia in 2004-2017 - Margrét Huld Hallsdóttir 1979-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46290</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Óbyggð víðerni utan miðhálendisins og fuglalíf: Helsta löggjöf og opinberu stefnuskjöl fyrir ákvarðanatöku um staðsetningu vindorkugarða</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46289</link>
      <description>Óbyggð víðerni utan miðhálendisins og fuglalíf: Helsta löggjöf og opinberu stefnuskjöl fyrir ákvarðanatöku um staðsetningu vindorkugarða - Brynhildur Sörensen 1992-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46289</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mass eruption rates in the explosive phase of the last five Hekla eruptions, comparison between observations and models.</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46291</link>
      <description>Mass eruption rates in the explosive phase of the last five Hekla eruptions, comparison between observations and models. - Kristín Þorsteinsd. Sonnentag 1991-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46291</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Áhrifaþættir líkamlegrar virkni barna og ungmenna með barnagigt og jafnaldra</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46285</link>
      <description>Áhrifaþættir líkamlegrar virkni barna og ungmenna með barnagigt og jafnaldra - Marey Jónasdóttir 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46285</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ostracods from Hvalfjörður, western Iceland: diversity and biomonitoring experiment</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46288</link>
      <description>Ostracods from Hvalfjörður, western Iceland: diversity and biomonitoring experiment - Hafrún Birta Hafliðadóttir 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46288</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kostnaðarhagkvæmi næringarmeðferðar fyrir vannærða aldraða sjúklinga: Niðurstöður úr HOMEFOOD rannsókninni</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46294</link>
      <description>Kostnaðarhagkvæmi næringarmeðferðar fyrir vannærða aldraða sjúklinga: Niðurstöður úr HOMEFOOD rannsókninni - Kristín Elísabet Halldórsdóttir 1987-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46294</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low level laser therapy – A review of clinical trials published 2013 - 2022</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46293</link>
      <description>Low level laser therapy – A review of clinical trials published 2013 - 2022 - Guðni Rúnar Jónsson 1989-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>„Við getum ekki fjárfest í sjóð bara því það eru konur sem stjórna honum.“ Þekking og viðhorf framkvæmdastjóra lífeyrissjóðanna á því hvort horfa eigi til kynjarsjónarmiða við fjárfestingar</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46292</link>
      <description>„Við getum ekki fjárfest í sjóð bara því það eru konur sem stjórna honum.“ Þekking og viðhorf framkvæmdastjóra lífeyrissjóðanna á því hvort horfa eigi til kynjarsjónarmiða við fjárfestingar - Arna Jónsdóttir 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46292</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jarðfræðikortlagning á Vatnafjallaeldstöðvarkerfinu</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46286</link>
      <description>Jarðfræðikortlagning á Vatnafjallaeldstöðvarkerfinu - Rakel Rún Karlsdóttir 1988-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46286</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Áhrif ólíkra umhverfisþátta á frammistöðu fólks</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46287</link>
      <description>Áhrif ólíkra umhverfisþátta á frammistöðu fólks - Rúnar Ísak Björgvinsson 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46287</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rannsókn á microRNA stýringu á KMT2D í Kabuki heilkenni 1</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46296</link>
      <description>Rannsókn á microRNA stýringu á KMT2D í Kabuki heilkenni 1 - Jóhann Örn Thorarensen 1997-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46296</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Examining The Relationship Between Urbanization and Food Security in China  Impacts on Accessibilty, Affordability, and Food Quality.</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46295</link>
      <description>Examining The Relationship Between Urbanization and Food Security in China  Impacts on Accessibilty, Affordability, and Food Quality. - Jiaqi Chen 1994-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46295</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sharing the safe operating space by using different allocation principles for sheep meat in Iceland. Iceland's share of the safe operating space for sheep meat production for the Planetary Boundary of climate change</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46278</link>
      <description>Sharing the safe operating space by using different allocation principles for sheep meat in Iceland. Iceland's share of the safe operating space for sheep meat production for the Planetary Boundary of climate change - Steffi Meisl 1987-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46278</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Euler angle approximation based on IMU sensor fusion</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46281</link>
      <description>Euler angle approximation based on IMU sensor fusion - Aron Ingi Sverrisson 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46281</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Potential During Utilization of High Temperature Saline Fluids in the Assal Geothermal Area (Djibouti)</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46284</link>
      <description>Scaling Potential During Utilization of High Temperature Saline Fluids in the Assal Geothermal Area (Djibouti) - Idil Souleiman Bouraleh 1993-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46284</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 3ka Búrfellshraun Lava Flow Field, Northeastern Iceland. Lava Dynamics and Surface Morphology.</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46283</link>
      <description>The 3ka Búrfellshraun Lava Flow Field, Northeastern Iceland. Lava Dynamics and Surface Morphology. - Diana Brum da Silveira Gibert Alvarez 1999-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46283</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Production of solar-grade silicon from metallurgical silicon by precipitation from aluminum melt</title>
      <link>https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46280</link>
      <description>Production of solar-grade silicon from metallurgical silicon by precipitation from aluminum melt - Bochang Chen 1998-</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://skemman.is/handle/1946/46280</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
